Guide to the Daniel Nilva Negatives PHOTOS.067
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VIII: Other Clients., 89679
  - Subseries VIII:A: American Veterans Committee., 89765
    - Eleanor Roosevelt; NY [American Veterans Committee. 14th National Convention.], May 1961; 89768 (Box 2, Item 1014)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt. Convention [American Veterans Committee] [Commodore Hotel], May 1961; 89767 (Box 4, Item 689)
    - [American Veterans Committee]; Award to Adlai Stevenson at US Mission to UN, Apr 20, 1962; 89766 (Box 2, Item 1015)
  - Subseries VIII:B: Jewish Consumptive Relief Association., 89692
    - City of Hope; Tuvim Dinner; Richard Wright [Assistant Secretary of State], Apr 21, 1951; 89764 (Box 2, Item 1016)
    - City of Hope; Torch of Hope Award to M. Tobin Waldorf Astoria, May 9, 1951; 89763 (Box 2, Item 1017)
    - City of Hope [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Luncheon CIO NY Director, Sep 21, 1951; 89762 (Box 2, Item 1019)
    - City of Hope [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association], Feb 10, 1952; 89761 (Box 2, Item 1020)
    - Deborah Sanitorium Luncheon; Waldorf-Astoria; [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] [Damaged negatives separated], Jun 17, 1954; cuid15263; 89760 (Box 9, Item 1862, Negative 1-13, Box 3)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Patient [from?] -- Holland. Idlewild [Airport?], Aug 14, 1954; 89759 (Box 3, Item 1036)
    - Deborah Hospital; Knitgoods Industry; [Separated as Damaged]; [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association], Dec 26, 1954; cuid15264; 89758 (Box 3, Item 1864, Box 9, Negative 2-8)
    - City of Hope Luncheon [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Hotel Pierre Roof. George Jessel [speaker?] and [Jennie] Grossinger, Jun 16, 1955; 89757 (Box 2, Item 1021)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]. Mrs. Henry [?] Epstein wife of Deputy Mayor, Sep 14, 1955; 89756 (Box 2, Item 1022)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]. Hotel Astor 8th Floor Ballroom; Honoring Ben[?] Paul; Belt Industry Fabulous Belts; Henry Schwartz, Local 40, Nathan Mintz, Ben Mintz, DC, Oct 27, 1955; 89755 (Box 2, Item 1023)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Plaza Hotel Mr. and Mrs. Epstein, Nov 15, 1955; 89754 (Box 2, Item 1024)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association], Bill Schnitzler Dinner Commodore, Nov 22, 1955; 89753 (Box 2, Item 1025)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Portrait of unidentified man], Oct 4, 1956; 89752 (Box 2, Item 1026)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] [Award to J. Irwin Shapiro.] Waldorf-Astoria, Nov 14, 1956; 89751 (Box 2, Item 1027)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] [Award to] Walter Reuther; Commodore Hotel, May 10, 1957; 89750 (Box 2, Item 1028)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Belt Industry, Commodore; Herb Novick, Oct 24, 1957; 89749 (Box 2, Item 1029)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] [Banquet at] Waldorf-Astoria, Dec 22, 1957; 89748 (Box 2, Item 1030)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Copy Neg Aerial View Hospital, Feb 17, 1958; 89747 (Box 2, Item 1031)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumpitve Relief Association] Groups [Group shots of women presenting a "Heart of Gold" certificate to another woman.], Mar 13, 1958; 89746 (Box 2, Item 1032)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Exec. Comm. Hotel Astor, Apr 27, 1958; 89745 (Box 3, Item 1033)
    - Deborah Sanitorium. [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]. Starks[?] Office [Group of people displaying a New York City mayor's proclamation; group includes shots of a little boy and a performer with a ventriloquist's dummy.], Apr 28, 1958; 89744 (Box 3, Item 1034)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Women's Comm. Hqtrs, Jun 2, 1958; 89743 (Box 3, Item 1037)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Mayor's Office, Paul Winchell, Jun 18, 1958; 89742 (Box 3, Item 1035)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Meeting; Waldorf, Oct 2, 1958; 89741 (Box 3, Item 1056)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Assocation]; Belt Industry; [Banquet at Hotel] Commodore, Oct 26, 1958; 89740 (Box 3, Item 1039)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] [Bronx] County, Oct 30, 1958; 89739 (Box 3, Item 1038)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Waldorf-Astoria, Nov 11, 1958; 89738 (Box 3, Item 1047)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]. Van Arsdale Dinner; Hotel Commodore, Dec 4, 1958; 89737 (Box 3, Item 1040)
    - Deborah Sanitorium WEVD [Radio] [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association.], Dec 20, 1958; 89736 (Box 1, Item 736)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Waldorf-Astoria [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association.], Dec 21, 1958; 89735 (Box 1, Item 737)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Ehler's Coffee [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association.], Jan 29, 1959; 89734 (Box 1, Item 738)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Jacob Weiss Returns to Israel [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association.], Mar 10, 1959; 89733 (Box 1, Item 739)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]. Coffee Industry Luncheon, Mar 10, 1959; 89732 (Box 3, Item 1041)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]. Queens Chapter Meeting, Mar 26, 1959; 89731 (Box 3, Item 1042)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Mayor's Office, Apr 21, 1959; 89730 (Box 3, Item 1043)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Israeli and Mother; Headquarters; [Separated as Damaged]; [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association], Jul 1, 1959; 89729 (Box 3, Item 1866)
    - DeborahSanitorium; Ehlers Dinner; [Damaged Negatives Separated]; [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association], Sep 28, 1959; cuid15265; 89728 (Box 3, Item 1865)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Assocation] [Bronx] Section; Concourse Plaza; Sullivan Dinner, Oct 21, 1959; 89727 (Box 3, Item 1044)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Dinner; Belt Industry, Oct 29, 1959; 89726 (Box 3, Item 1045)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Conf. Grain Co. [?] [Award to Rene Fribourg], Oct 30, 1959; 89725 (Box 3, Item 1048)
    - Deborah Sanitorium Knitgoods Industry Committee, Nov 1, 1959; cuid15266; 89724 (Box 3, Item 1046, Box 9, Negative 3)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Knitgoods Committee [Separated as damaged]; [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association], Nov 10, 1959; cuid15267; 89723 (Box 3, Item 1863, Box 9, Negative 1-4)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Police Donation; [Separated from Damaged Negs], Dec 18, 1959; cuid15268; 89722 (Box 3, Item 1861, Box 9, Negative 3-4)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Copy Neg; Sanitorium; Thomas Mackell, [1960s?]; 89721 (Box 3, Item 1071)
    - Deborah [ Hospital and Sanitorium] [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Poster ["Your Deborah Tree of Life … Give It Life"], Jan 8, 1960; 89720 (Box 3, Item 1053)
    - Deborah [Hospital] Copy Neg; [Separated as Damaged], Feb 17, 1960; cuid15269; 89719 (Box 3, Item 1860, Box 9, Negative 1)
    - Deborah Hospital; Copy Neg; Head and Painting; [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; [Separated as Damaged], Mar 4, 1960; cuid15270; 89718 (Box 3, Item 1859, Box 9, Negative 1-2)
    - Deborah Sanitorium and Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Annual Convention; Statler Hilton, Apr 25, 1960; 89717 (Box 3, Item 1052)
    - Deborah Sanitorium and Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Proclamation [Mayor's] Stark[?], Apr 26, 1960; 89716 (Box 3, Item 1050)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Deborah Square; 4 Neg [Group of people poses on wooden platform erected at Times Square (with Hotel Astor visible in background) below a street sign that reads: "Deborah Square.", May 16, 1960; 89715 (Box 3, Item 1049)
    - Deborah Sanitorium and Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Members Meeting, May 19, 1960; 89714 (Box 3, Item 1051)
    - Deborah Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Luncheon; Waldorf, Jun 21, 1960; 89713 (Box 3, Item 1055)
    - Deborah Sanitorium and Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Rosenberg -- Quillers[Quillins?], Jun 22, 1960; 89712 (Box 3, Item 1058)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Astor Luncheon, Jun 22, 1960; 89711 (Box 3, Item 1057)
    - Deborah Sanitorium and Hosptial [Jewish Consumptive Rellief Association]; Wolf Testimonial Dinner; Waldorf-Astoria, Sep 29, 1960; 89710 (Box 3, Item 1059)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Commodore; Belt Industry, Oct 18, 1960; 89709 (Box 3, Item 1054)
    - Deborah Sanitorium and Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Conc. Plaza; [Award presented to Abraham] Bernstein; State Senator [Community Service Award], Nov 19, 1960; 89708 (Box 3, Item 1060)
    - Deborah Sanitorium and Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Knitgoods Industry, Waldorf, Nov 23, 1960; 89707 (Box 3, Item 1061)
    - Deborah Hospital and Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Annual Affair; Waldorf-Astoria, Dec 18, 1960; 89706 (Box 3, Item 1062)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association]; Jacob Hoffman and Wife; Exodus--"Rider", Apr 25, 1961; 89705 (Box 3, Item 1063)
    - Deborah Hospital and Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Mayor's Proclamation, May 1, 1961; 89704 (Box 3, Item 1064)
    - Deborah Hospital and Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] 34 Luncheon; Commodore, Jun 20, 1961; 89703 (Box 3, Item 1065)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Queens Village; Arthurs [? Autumn?]; State Senator Mackell, Jun 22, 1961; 89702 (Box 3, Item 1066)
    - Deborah Hospital and Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Abbey Rosenberg Dinner; Waldorf-Astoria, Oct 4, 1961; 89701 (Box 3, Item 1067)
    - Deborah Hospital and Sanitorium [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Belt Industry; Commodore, Oct 17, 1961; 89700 (Box 3, Item 1068)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Mintz; Ukranian Jewish Meeting; Woodstock Hotel, Oct 25, 1961; 89699 (Box 3, Item 1069)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Knitgoods Committee Meeting, New Yorker [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association.], Nov 14, 1961; 89698 (Box 1, Item 740)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] 39th Anniversary Dinner; Commordore Hotel, Dec 17, 1961; 89697 (Box 3, Item 1070)
    - Deborah Sanitorium; Mayor's Proclamation, Molly Picon [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association], Apr 23, 1962; 89696 (Box 1, Item 741)
    - Deborah Hospital; Commodore, Molly Picon Table[?] [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] "Award to [Molly Picon]; M.P. Speaking; M.P. husband…...", Jun 21, 1962; 89695 (Box 1, Item 742)
    - [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] Deborah Hospital, Queens Banquet; Sam [?sky] [Shots include three union officials receiving the Deborah Hospital "Heart of Gold" award certificates: Louis L. Levi, Jun 23, 1962; 89694 (Box 1, Item 743)
    - Deborah Hospital [Jewish Consumptive Relief Association] [Fan] Ziskin, Jul 15, 1962; 89693 (Box 1, Item 744)
  - Subseries VIII:C: Leather Craft Guild., 89690
    - Leather Craft Guild [?] 25 W. 53 St., [1940s?]; 89691 (Box 1, Item 552)
  - Subseries VIII:D: New York State Department of Labor., 89688
    - NY State Department Noah Walter, 80 Center [Centre?] NYC, [1950s?]; 89689 (Box 2, Item 930)
  - Subseries VIII:E: Produce Exchange., 89685
    - Mort Lawrence, Produce Exchange, Interiors and Headshots, Oct 30, 1950; 89687 (Box 2, Item 944)
    - Produce Exchange [party or reception], Nov 24, 1959; 89686 (Box 2, Item 946)
  - Subseries VIII:F: Rural Schools., 89683
    - Rural Schools Luncheon, Hotel Commadore, Nov 19, 1955; 89684 (Box 1, Item 650)
  - Subseries VIII:G: WEVD Radio., 89680
    - [WEVD] [2 men doing a radio broadcast?], [1930s?]; 89682 (Box 1, Item 598)
    - Political / La Guardia/Thomas Dewey/ Alex Rose/ Dewey & Antonini [WEVD Radio], 1938; 89681 (Box 1, Item 554)
- Series IX: Personal., 89664
  - H. Fox Frances and Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva, Daniel Nilva's first wife], [1930s?]; 89678 (Box 1, Item 668)
  - Mildred [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva] at Piano, Dec 1, 1939; 89677 (Box 1, Item 665)
  - Mildred Nilva [copy shot of image of Mildred Nilva as a young girl], [1940s?]; 89676 (Box 1, Item 666)
  - Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva], [1940s?]; 89675 (Box 4, Item 664)
  - Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva, ] [Outside (?) Summer Portraits], [1940s?]; 89674 (Box 4, Item 663)
  - Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva], [1940s?]; 89673 (Box 4, Item 662)
  - Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva], [1940s?]; 89672 (Box 4, Item 661)
  - Millie [Nilva?] [Portrait with 3 other women and 1 man], [1940s?]; 89671 (Box 4, Item 659)
  - Edie, Jimmy, Dan [Nilva?], Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva], [1940s?]; 89670 (Box 4, Item 658)
  - Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva], [1940s?]; 89669 (Box 4, Item 657)
  - Dan [Nilva?], Edie, Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva], Jimmy, [1940s?]; 89668 (Box 4, Item 656)
  - Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva], [1940s?]; 89667 (Box 4, Item 655)
  - Millie [probably Alice "Millie" Nilva] [copy shot of letter written in French], Sep 7, 1949; 89666 (Box 1, Item 667)
  - Self [Daniel Nilva?] and Drh[?] [Possibly Daniel Nilva, and dog; Portrait: unidentified man -- "Drh"?], [1950s?]; 89665 (Box 4, Item 660)
- Series X: Unprocessed Materials, 487327 (Box 5, Box 6)
  - Unprocessed 35mm, 120, 2 1/4, and 4 x 5 negatives., 487328 (Box 5)
  - Unprocessed 5 x 7 and 8 x 10 Negatives, 487329 (Box 6)